Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up the IK for our right foot. And now,
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们成功地为我们的右脚设置了IK。而现在、
both of our feet are snapping to the climbable surface when we are climbing. And that's great.
我们的两只脚都能在攀爬时紧贴在可攀爬表面。而这很好。
Now that we have the feet placement ready, next thing we need to take care of the hands.
现在我们已经准备好了脚的位置，接下来我们需要处理手的问题。
And I think you are more than ready to take it from here. So your challenge is simple.
我想你们已经准备好了，可以开始行动了。所以你的挑战很简单。
I'd like you to handle the IK for both of the hands. They should be the exact same as
我希望你能处理两只手的IK。它们应该与我们的脚的IK完全相同。
our foot IK. So feel free to use them as a reference if you need. Alright, pause the
我们的脚的IK。所以，如果你需要的话，可以随意使用它们作为参考。好了，暂停
video now and give this a go or come back if you need help.
暂停视频，试试这个，如果需要帮助再来。
Welcome back. How did that go for you? Hopefully at this point, you have a fully functional
欢迎回来。你做得怎么样了？希望在这一点上，你有一个功能齐全的
climb IK. And don't worry if you ran into any issues. Let's look at how I would do it.
攀登 IK。如果你遇到了什么问题，也不用担心。让我们来看看我是怎么做的。
So double click to open this climb IK. First thing, I'm going to organize these variables.
双击来打开这个攀岩IK。首先，我将组织这些变量。
So I'm going to select this foot_LR_TargetOffset. Give it a category. So I'm going to change
所以我将选择这个foot_LR_TargetOffset。给它一个类别。所以我将改变
its name to foot. And I'm going to move this one to the same category. Move this one as
它的名字是foot。我将把这个移到同一类别。把这个也移到
well. And this one. Alright, I'm going to hide these variables. And next thing, I'm
也是。还有这个。好了，我要隐藏这些变量。接下来，我将
going to duplicate this function. Plug this one to here. Then I'm going to change this
复制这个函数。把这个插入到这里。然后我将把这个
to IK_HandL. And promote this to a variable. Change its name to Hand_L_TargetOffset. And
到IK_HandL。并将其提升为一个变量。把它的名字改为Hand_L_TargetOffset。然后
connect this bin to here. Then go to next step. I'm going to reset it if we are not
将这个bin连接到这里。然后进入下一个步骤。我将重置它，如果我们不在
climbing. So set it in here. And next thing, I'll need to interpolate it. Duplicate this
攀登。所以把它设置在这里。而接下来，我需要对它进行插值。复制这个
interpolate node. Plug this into socket B. And I'm going to connect this time to here.
插值节点。把这个插入插座B，而我这次要连接到这里。
And add the root ground node. Move it down a bit. And promote the result of it into another
并添加根地节点。把它往下移一点。并把它的结果推广到另一个
variable. And change its name to Hand_L_CurrentOffset. And drag out this variable. Get it. Plug it
变量。并把它的名字改为Hand_L_CurrentOffset。然后拖出这个变量。得到它。插入它
into socket A. And connect this bin to here. And go down. Right mouse button click to bring
将这个垃圾桶连接到这里。然后往下走。鼠标右键点击，把
out the modified transform node. And connect this one to here. Now for the element 0, I'm
出修改后的转换节点。将这个节点连接到这里。现在对于0号元素，我将
going to change its name to IK_HandL. And for the transform here, I'm going to drag out
将它的名字改为IK_HandL。对于这里的变换，我将拖出
this current offset. Get it. Plug it into translation. And change its mode to additive
这个当前的偏移量。得到它。把它插入转换。并把它的模式改为加法的
global. And move down to full body IK. I'm going to add another element. Change its name
全局。并向下移动到全身IK。我将添加另一个元素。把它的名字改为
to Hand_L. And duplicate this get transform node. Change it to IK_HandL. Plug this transform
为Hand_L。并复制这个得到的变换节点。把它改成IK_HandL。把这个变换
into here. Alright. Click compile. And we have the same warning. I'm going to ignore
到这里。好的。点击编译。我们有同样的警告。我将会忽略
it this time. And I'm going to press play in here. So go to the surface. Press F. And
它这次。我将在这里按下播放键。所以到表面去。按F。
I'm going to try to move. So I think the offset is too much for this left hand. I'm going
我将尝试移动。所以我觉得这个偏移量对这个左手来说太大。我打算
to lower it down a bit. So go back to this graph. I'm going to give this target location
把它放低一点。所以回到这个图形上。我将给这个目标位置
offset a default value of 5 minutes. And click compile. And test this again. And try to move.
偏移量的默认值为5分钟。然后点击编译。再测试一下这个。并尝试移动。
I think 5 units works. Maybe a bit more. I'm going to change this to 7 units. And click
我认为5个单位可以。也许更多一点。我打算把它改成7个单位。然后点击
compile. Try again. Yeah, I think 7 units works better. And that's the left hand ready.
编译。再试一次。是的，我认为7个单位效果更好。这就是左手的准备。
Next thing I'm going to take care of the right hand. So select this function again. Duplicate
接下来我要处理右手的问题。所以再次选择这个函数。复制
it. Connect this pin to here. Change this one to IK_HandR. And promote it to variable.
它。把这个引脚连接到这里。把这个改为IK_HandR。并将其提升为变量。
Change its name to Hand_R_TargetOffset. Before I forget, I'm going to move these variables
把它的名字改为Hand_R_TargetOffset。在我忘记之前，我将把这些变量
into its own group. So change the category to Hand. Move this one to there. Move this
到它自己的组中。所以把类别改为手。把这个移到那里。把这个
one as well. And connect this pin to here. Then next thing I'm going to reset it. So
一个也是。并将这个针脚连接到这里。然后，接下来我将重置它。所以
drag out this target offset. Set it. Connect this pin to here. Then interpolate this value.
拖出这个目标偏移。设置它。把这个引脚连接到这里。然后把这个值插进去。
So duplicate this node. Drag out this target offset. Plug it into socket B. Promote the
所以复制这个节点。拖出这个目标偏移。把它插入插座B，促进
result into another variable. Change its name to Hand_R_CurrentOffset. And move it to this
结果进入另一个变量。把它的名字改为Hand_R_CurrentOffset。并把它移到这个
hand category. Drag it out. Get it. And plug it into socket A. Organize these nodes a bit
手的类别。把它拖出来。得到它。把它插入插座A，把这些节点整理一下
and connect this pin to here. And drag out this time. Plug it in here. Add the rerun
并把这个针脚连接到这里。再把这次的拖出来。把它插在这里。添加重新运行
now. Alright, that's the interpreting done. And next thing I'm going to modify is transform.
现在。好了，这就是解释工作的完成。接下来我要修改的是变换。
So right mouse button click. Type in modify transform. Connect this pin to here. And inside
所以，鼠标右键单击。键入修改变换。把这个引脚连接到这里。而在
the flip dropdown, change this name to Hand_R. Change this node to Additive Global. Drag out
翻转下拉菜单，把这个名字改为Hand_R。把这个节点改成Additive Global。拖出
this current offset. Get it. Set the translation. This is the exact same as the bone previous
这个电流偏移。得到它。设置翻译。这与之前的骨头完全一样
to this one. And I'm going to scroll down to this full body IK. Add one more element.
到这个。我将向下滚动到这个全身的IK。再添加一个元素。
Change its name to Hand_R. And get hold of this IK_HandR. Plug the transform into here
把它的名字改为Hand_R。并掌握这个IK_HandR。将变换插入这里
and we should be good to go. Click compile. Click it again. And go back to my level. I'm
然后我们就可以开始了。点击编译。再点击一下。然后回到我的水平。我将
going to press play. And try to climb up. So I think for our right hand, I need to increase
要按下播放键。然后试着往上爬。所以我想对于我们的右手，我需要增加
the offset distance. Now instead of 7 units, I'm going to change this to 9 units and click
偏移距离。现在，我将把它改为9个单位，而不是7个单位，然后点击
compile. Alright, test this again. So try to climb up. Yeah, I think it looks good enough.
编译。好了，再测试一下。所以试着爬起来。是的，我认为它看起来足够好。
I think when we're climbing our right hand is clipping through a little bit but I think
我想当我们爬升的时候，我们的右手有一点被剪掉了，但我认为
we don't need to worry about that. This already looks good enough. And after some play testing,
我们不需要担心这个问题。这看起来已经足够好了。经过一些游戏测试，我注意到我的代码里面有一个错误、
I notice an error inside of my code for this control rig. So I'm going to double click
我注意到在这个控制装置的代码中存在一个错误。所以我打算双击
to open it and zoom in to this target offset. So I shouldn't be resetting these values in
来打开它并放大到这个目标偏移。所以我不应该在这里重新设置这些值
here. Instead, I'm going to select all of these nodes, cut them, and paste them in here.
这里。相反，我要选择所有这些节点，把它们剪切下来，然后粘贴到这里。
So when this main condition is false, I'm going to reset all of these vectors and connect
因此，当这个主要条件为假时，我将重置所有这些向量，并将这个引脚连接到这里。
this pin to here and delete these two nodes. So when this condition should do climbIkTrace
这个引脚连接到这里，并删除这两个节点。所以当这个条件应该做climbIkTrace时
is false, I'm going to reset all of these values and it shouldn't be done after this
是假的，我将重置所有这些值，它不应该在这个
sequence node. Alright, I'm going to click compile. And there's another issue that I
序列节点之后。好了，我要点击编译了。还有一个问题，我
noticed. So I'm going to click play and I'm going to try to climb to the right. So you
注意到的另一个问题。所以我将点击播放，并尝试向右爬。所以你
can see while I'm passing through this area, my right hand is clipping through the surface
你可以看到，当我通过这个区域时，我的右手正从表面上划过。
and to figure out the reason behind it, thanks to the debug function that we set up inside
为了弄清楚这背后的原因，感谢我们在控制装置中设置的调试功能。
of our control rig, we can easily figure out why. So I'm going to go back to it. Then I'm
我们可以很容易地找出原因。所以我将回到它。然后我
going to go to, I'm going to take the show debug shape and I'm going to click play again
我要去，我将采取显示调试形状，我将再次点击播放
and enter the climb state. Notice that I can no longer see the debug shape and that's because
并进入爬升状态。注意，我已经看不到调试形状了，这是因为
I've just restarted my editor. I'll need to type in the console command again. So it'll
我刚刚重新启动了我的编辑器。我需要再次输入控制台的命令。所以它将是
be a underscore enum node underscore control rig debug one and hit enter. And there's my
是一个underscore枚举节点underscore控制设备debug one，然后点击回车。这就是我的
debug line. I'm going to climb to the right and you can see for a single frame there,
调试线。我要爬到右边去，你可以看到那里有一个单帧、
we don't have a valid head location. So to fix that issue, we can simply increase the
我们没有一个有效的头部位置。所以为了解决这个问题，我们可以简单地增加
trace radius for our severe trace. So I'm going to go inside of this function and zoom
追踪的半径。因此，我将进入这个函数并放大
in to this severe trace by object types. So if I increase this radius to 20 units and
按对象类型放大到这个严重的跟踪。所以，如果我把这个半径增加到20个单位，然后
click compile, then try again. And this time it gets much better. And now every time when
点击编译，然后再试一次。这一次，它变得更好了。现在每次当
we pass this area, we'll have a valid head location. And with our current set up, now
我们都会有一个有效的头部位置。以我们现在的设置，现在
if I try to move to a straight angle like this, you can see both of our hands and feet
如果我试图像这样以一个直角移动，你可以看到我们的手和脚
are trying to reach the surface in here. And we can even climb up on an angle like this.
都试图到达这里的表面。而且我们甚至可以像这样以一个角度爬上去。
But again, I don't think we should be able to do this during climbing, but this is a
但同样，我认为我们不应该在攀爬过程中做这个，但这是一个
perfect area to test our control rig. And if this is what you want and you like to make
但这是一个测试我们控制装置的完美区域。如果这是你想要的，而且你喜欢使
this much better. So I'm going to slowly move to the left and go to the right. You
这要好得多。所以我要慢慢地向左移动，向右走。你可以看到
can see when I'm at a spot like this, because our severe trace does not have a valid head
你可以看到，当我在这样一个地方的时候，因为我们的严重跟踪没有一个有效的头部位置
location, our right hand is in the air. So if there's something they want to prevent,
位置，我们的右手就在空中。因此，如果有什么他们想要防止的东西、
you want to snap our hand the whole time, you can either keep increasing the trace radius
你想一直扣住我们的手，你可以继续增加我们的严重追踪的半径
for our severe trace, or you can perform a second trace here to find the climbable surface.
或者你可以在这里进行第二次追踪以找到可攀登的表面。
I'm going to leave that as an optional challenge to you. I'm sure at this point, you know
我打算把这个作为一个可选的挑战留给你。我相信在这一点上，你一定知道
how to implement that by yourself. And since we've just increased the trace radius for
如何自己实现它。因为我们刚刚增加了严重追踪的半径。
our severe trace, if I'm climbing on a surface like this, I'm going to try to move to the
如果我在这样的表面上爬行，我将尝试向右移动。
right. You can see as I'm moving my head location will be above the character's head. So for
右边。你可以看到在我移动的过程中，我的头部位置将在角色的头部上方。所以对于
a surface like this, the radius is too large. And this is also something that you can dive
这样的一个表面，半径太大了。如果你对这个问题感兴趣的话，你也可以在后面深入研究一下。
into later yourself if you are interested in resolving this issue. So for example, instead
如果你对解决这个问题感兴趣的话，你也可以稍后深入研究一下。因此，举例来说
of using a fixed value for our severe trace, you can change it dynamically depending on
你可以根据我们的角色所处的表面，动态地改变它，而不是使用一个固定的值来进行严厉的追踪。
what kind of surface that our character is on. And the radius that I'm using for surfaces
我们的角色在什么样的表面上。而我对表面使用的半径
like this will work just fine. And that's pretty much it for our ClimbIK. We can even
这样就可以正常工作了。这就是我们的ClimbIK的基本情况。我们甚至可以
climb to the border of this map if we want. And we can climb back in. And later if you
如果我们想的话，可以爬到地图的边界。我们还可以爬回来。以后如果你
notice any other issues, you can use our debug functions to come up with your own solution
注意到任何其他的问题，你可以使用我们的调试功能来想出你自己的解决方案
to solve it. And starting from next lecture, we are going to look at how we can add in
来解决它。从下一节课开始，我们将研究如何在我们的攀登系统中加入
more features to our climbing system. I'll see you in the next lecture.
更多的功能到我们的爬坡系统中。我们在下一讲再见。
[END]
[结束]